<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mission on Console Labs</title><link>https://log.console.so/tags/mission/</link><description>Recent content in mission on Console Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://log.console.so/tags/mission/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mission</title><link>https://log.console.so/mission/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://log.console.so/mission/</guid><description>&lt;p>// thought about future + software + finance
Believe in the future where everyone has to involve in financial activity&lt;/p>
&lt;p>// and we want to
Building financial-centric software&lt;/p>
&lt;p>//
Part of the Dwarves&lt;/p>
&lt;p>// build and chill
Building a product team&lt;/p>
&lt;p>// the financial data layer&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="financial-centric">Financial-centric &lt;a href="#financial-centric">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Recognizing the inevitability of financial activities in the future, we dedicate our efforts to building software that safeguards and enriches people’s financial journeys.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We know dealing with money is going to be a big part of the future, so we’re dedicated to making software that helps peeps do it safely and navigate through the finance world.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Secure the Bag&lt;/strong>: Every creation of ours is your key to handling moolah safely and getting those financial gains.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Safe and Sound&lt;/strong>: Everything we make aims to give people safe and easy access to handle their money and learn more about it.
Crafting software that helps peeps navigate the finance world safely is our jam!&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Every solution we develop is centered around providing safe, secure, and empowering access to financial resources and knowledge, preparing individuals for a flourishing financial future.
We’re looking at a future where everyone’s got their money game on point. We’re here to build the tech that makes finance a breeze, so everyone can make those smart moves and get that bread.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We see a future where everyone’s in tune with their finances. That’s why we’re here, building the cool tech that makes understanding and accessing finance a breeze, helping everyone make those smart, secure money moves!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>