<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Console Labs</title><link>https://log.console.so/</link><description>Recent content on Console Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@console.so (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@console.so (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2023 ConsoleLabs.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://log.console.so/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>contributors</title><link>https://log.console.so/contributors/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@console.so (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://log.console.so/contributors/</guid><description>Here are people at Console Labs and contributors who give hands to make our experiments happened
core neko-san: twitter, bsky hnh: github vincent: github tono: twitter contributors anna minh.cloud 0xLight owltrovert PAMsheep phucld: github trkhoi: github anhnh: github huynk: github phucnh: github Mashiro: github quang: github bien: github namnhce: github minhth: github vdhieu: github haongo138: github monotykamary: github Pod Town DAO 𝖘𝖚𝖓 𝖋𝖎𝖗𝖊 [𝖓𝖋𝖆] digdug bimps: twitter</description></item><item><title>Shape Up</title><link>https://log.console.so/blog/shape-up/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@console.so (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://log.console.so/blog/shape-up/</guid><description>Exploring We build up knowledge through collective team learning. This page is where lab members share their explorations of the financial world.
Every week, we host a presentation to discuss our findings. This not only aids memory recall but also fosters a lasting learning culture within the team, keeping us updated on market trends.
We cover a range of topics, from basics like &amp;lsquo;6 jars budgeting methodology&amp;rsquo; to more current subjects like &amp;lsquo;web3 liquidity techniques&amp;rsquo;.</description></item><item><title>emoji</title><link>https://log.console.so/experiments/emoji/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@console.so (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://log.console.so/experiments/emoji/</guid><description/></item><item><title>kekk</title><link>https://log.console.so/experiments/kekk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@console.so (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://log.console.so/experiments/kekk/</guid><description/></item><item><title>mochi</title><link>https://log.console.so/experiments/mochi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@console.so (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://log.console.so/experiments/mochi/</guid><description/></item><item><title>neko</title><link>https://log.console.so/experiments/neko/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@console.so (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://log.console.so/experiments/neko/</guid><description/></item><item><title>pod town</title><link>https://log.console.so/experiments/pod-town/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@console.so (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://log.console.so/experiments/pod-town/</guid><description/></item><item><title>WAGMI comics</title><link>https://log.console.so/experiments/wagmi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@console.so (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://log.console.so/experiments/wagmi/</guid><description/></item><item><title>About Us</title><link>https://log.console.so/about/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@console.so (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://log.console.so/about/</guid><description>Intro We’re Console Labs. We’re all about that finance and making things fun. We’re diving deep into tech, data, web3, blockchain, and jotting down all the cool stuff we find, hoping to whip up something rad for everyone online.
Peep our philosophy and mission, or keep it fresh by catching our monthly updates. Oh, and btw, we’re like a sibling to Dwarves.
Website 💻 This site is where we show our face to the world.</description></item><item><title>API-first development</title><link>https://log.console.so/playbook/api-first/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@console.so (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://log.console.so/playbook/api-first/</guid><description>by hnh
Background @Console Labs, our primary goal is to rapidly introduce new features and gather user feedback as quickly as possible. We understand that this approach isn&amp;rsquo;t flawless and can lead to regression bugs. However, at this stage of our product development, we are content with this strategy.
The challenge arises when we aim to develop something new within a short timeframe, typically one week or even just two days.</description></item><item><title>Data layer</title><link>https://log.console.so/playbook/data-layer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@console.so (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://log.console.so/playbook/data-layer/</guid><description>by hnh
This data layer serves as the central source of information for various features such as tickers, price alerts, and token details. These features rely on the data within this layer to provide accurate and up-to-date information to users. In essence, it&amp;rsquo;s like the beating heart of the mochi ecosystem, ensuring that all the essential data is readily available for users to access and use.
Raw Data The raw data that powers our system originates from blockchain transaction data, which we can retrieve from various RPC sources.</description></item><item><title>Leverage Mochi balances</title><link>https://log.console.so/playbook/integrate-mochi-balances/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@console.so (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://log.console.so/playbook/integrate-mochi-balances/</guid><description>by hnh, minh_cloud</description></item><item><title>log</title><link>https://log.console.so/blog/log/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@console.so (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://log.console.so/blog/log/</guid><description>A list of changes and updates to our experiments.
RSS feed, regular updates. Newsletter for frens, monthly updates. September 2023</description></item><item><title>Meaningful commit message</title><link>https://log.console.so/playbook/meaningful-commit/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@console.so (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://log.console.so/playbook/meaningful-commit/</guid><description>by hnh
Problems &amp;amp; Background Have you ever been frustrated by reading an app&amp;rsquo;s changelog that&amp;rsquo;s full of unhelpful information? It&amp;rsquo;s like they don&amp;rsquo;t care about their product or their users. You might have seen changelogs like this:
2.11.4
Some bugs fixed or
Fix bugs and improve UI/UX These changelogs are confusing and don&amp;rsquo;t provide any meaningful insights for users. Changelogs are meant for people, not machines. They serve as a way for us to communicate with our users.</description></item><item><title>Philosophy</title><link>https://log.console.so/philosophy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@console.so (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://log.console.so/philosophy/</guid><description>We’re all about shaping a future where tech is chill, super fun, and all about those money vibes. Here’s the scoop on the four main vibes guiding our crew:
Small but Sharp 🔍 We’re digging the idea of creating things that are small but ace at what they do. We aim for simplicity and effectiveness, making sure every tool we make nails its job and stands out in its own way.</description></item><item><title>Continuous Integration</title><link>https://log.console.so/playbook/ci-cd/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@console.so (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://log.console.so/playbook/ci-cd/</guid><description>by quang, hnh
What Continuous Integration (CI) is a development practice where developers integrate code into a shared repository frequently, preferably several times a day. Each integration can then be verified by an automated build and automated tests. While automated testing is not strictly part of CI it is typically implied.
One of the key benefits of integrating regularly is that you can detect errors quickly and locate them more easily.</description></item><item><title>Format a Mochi profile &amp; Number</title><link>https://log.console.so/playbook/format-profile-number/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@console.so (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://log.console.so/playbook/format-profile-number/</guid><description>When it comes to a UI rendering, there is no such things as a &amp;ldquo;correct way&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Integrate new chain</title><link>https://log.console.so/playbook/add-new-chains/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@console.so (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://log.console.so/playbook/add-new-chains/</guid><description>by hnh, vhbien
In the rapidly evolving blockchain industry, it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to keep up with the pace of change. Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick overview of how we seamlessly integrate new chains into the Mochi system, with the caveat that this method is specific to EVM-based blockchains:
Product Preparation Pull raw data into clickhouse Ticker, Watchlist Token Info Wallet tracking on this new chain Show assets in profile Transfer / Tip / Airdrop / Payme / Paylink Withdraw Deposit [0] Product Preparation In this section, most of the tasks require manual handling.</description></item><item><title>Mission</title><link>https://log.console.so/mission/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@console.so (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://log.console.so/mission/</guid><description>// thought about future + software + finance Believe in the future where everyone has to involve in financial activity
// and we want to Building financial-centric software
// Part of the Dwarves
// build and chill Building a product team
// the financial data layer
Financial-centric Recognizing the inevitability of financial activities in the future, we dedicate our efforts to building software that safeguards and enriches people’s financial journeys.</description></item><item><title>Shared UI library in multiple platforms</title><link>https://log.console.so/playbook/shared-ui-lib/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@console.so (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://log.console.so/playbook/shared-ui-lib/</guid><description>by hnh
Background Earlier this year, we introduced a new version of Telegram for Mochi, but it came with some new challenges.
Up until now, we&amp;rsquo;ve been using a single backend system to support all of our services. This approach was taken to ensure a smooth experience for both users and engineers across different platforms. However, a problem arose when it came to the user interface. We found ourselves dealing with two different sets of rules (Discord &amp;amp; Telegram) for how the interface should look and behave.</description></item></channel></rss>