<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>guideline on Console Labs</title><link>https://log.console.so/tags/guideline/</link><description>Recent content in guideline on Console Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://log.console.so/tags/guideline/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>API-first development</title><link>https://log.console.so/playbook/api-first/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://log.console.so/playbook/api-first/</guid><description>by hnh
Background @Console Labs, our primary goal is to rapidly introduce new features and gather user feedback as quickly as possible. We understand that this approach isn&amp;rsquo;t flawless and can lead to regression bugs. However, at this stage of our product development, we are content with this strategy.
The challenge arises when we aim to develop something new within a short timeframe, typically one week or even just two days.</description></item><item><title>Data layer</title><link>https://log.console.so/playbook/data-layer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://log.console.so/playbook/data-layer/</guid><description>by hnh
This data layer serves as the central source of information for various features such as tickers, price alerts, and token details. These features rely on the data within this layer to provide accurate and up-to-date information to users. In essence, it&amp;rsquo;s like the beating heart of the mochi ecosystem, ensuring that all the essential data is readily available for users to access and use.
Raw Data The raw data that powers our system originates from blockchain transaction data, which we can retrieve from various RPC sources.</description></item><item><title>How to levarage Mochi Balances</title><link>https://log.console.so/playbook/how-to-integrate-mochi-balances/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://log.console.so/playbook/how-to-integrate-mochi-balances/</guid><description>by hnh, minh_cloud</description></item><item><title>Integrate new chain</title><link>https://log.console.so/playbook/integrate-new-chains/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://log.console.so/playbook/integrate-new-chains/</guid><description>by hnh, vhbien
In the rapidly evolving blockchain industry, it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to keep up with the pace of change. Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick overview of how we seamlessly integrate new chains into the Mochi system, with the caveat that this method is specific to EVM-based blockchains:
Product Preparation Pull raw data into clickhouse Ticker, Watchlist Token Info Wallet tracking on this new chain Show assets in profile Transfer / Tip / Airdrop / Payme / Paylink Withdraw Deposit [0] Product Preparation In this section, most of the tasks require manual handling.</description></item></channel></rss>