<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>workflow on Console Labs</title><link>https://log.console.so/tags/workflow/</link><description>Recent content in workflow on Console Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>han@console.so (Han Ngo)</managingEditor><webMaster>han@console.so (Han Ngo)</webMaster><copyright>© 2023 ConsoleLabs.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://log.console.so/tags/workflow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pod Town Sunday</title><link>https://log.console.so/playbook/podtownsunday/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@console.so (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://log.console.so/playbook/podtownsunday/</guid><description>After a year with Pod Town Metaverse, we discovered that an informed and involved community is key to supporting our project. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s sharing news, being an advocate, or actively participating, a supportive community plays a vital role in a project&amp;rsquo;s success. Your insights and feedback matter, shaping our development. That&amp;rsquo;s why Console Labs isn&amp;rsquo;t just for us – it&amp;rsquo;s for the entire community.
With the aim to make Console Labs become a community-driven team, we decided to take advantage of the Pod Town community which had been enriched through the NFT season, to pose every update of our products.</description></item><item><title>A Scrum Sprint</title><link>https://log.console.so/playbook/workflow/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@console.so (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://log.console.so/playbook/workflow/</guid><description>We work in an 1-week sprint at console labs. At the end of the sprint, we do the review and public announcement.
A typical sprint of the Console Labs:
8:30 am, Monday: There is a planning session between CEO and the product team. 2 pm, Wednesday: The product team review the work in the first half of the week. 4 pm, Friday: The team review all the work in the week, then release the weekly changelog at 6 pm.</description></item><item><title>Meaningful commit message</title><link>https://log.console.so/playbook/meaningful-commit/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@console.so (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://log.console.so/playbook/meaningful-commit/</guid><description>Problems &amp;amp; Background Have you ever been frustrated by reading an app&amp;rsquo;s changelog that&amp;rsquo;s full of unhelpful information? It&amp;rsquo;s like they don&amp;rsquo;t care about their product or their users. You might have seen changelogs like this:
2.11.4
Some bugs fixed or
Fix bugs and improve UI/UX These changelogs are confusing and don&amp;rsquo;t provide any meaningful insights for users. Changelogs are meant for people, not machines. They serve as a way for us to communicate with our users.</description></item><item><title>Continuous Integration</title><link>https://log.console.so/playbook/ci-cd/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>han@console.so (Han Ngo)</author><guid>https://log.console.so/playbook/ci-cd/</guid><description>What Continuous Integration (CI) is a development practice where developers integrate code into a shared repository frequently, preferably several times a day. Each integration can then be verified by an automated build and automated tests. While automated testing is not strictly part of CI it is typically implied.
One of the key benefits of integrating regularly is that you can detect errors quickly and locate them more easily. As each change introduced is typically small, pinpointing the specific change that introduced a defect can be done quickly.</description></item></channel></rss>